Jennifer Brana

PHD STUDENT, CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

■ jbrana@cs.cmu.edu | ★ jenniferbrana.github.io | 🎧 JenniferBrana | 🛅 jenniferbrana

Research Interests

I am interested in the intersection of hardware and software systems, particularly in the areas of parallel computing and heterogeneous systems. My aim is to increase the scalability and sustainability of future computing systems.

Research areas: computer architecture; computer systems; memory systems; sustainability.

Education __

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D in Computer Science

June 2023 - Present

Advisor: Nathan Beckmann
University of Portland

Portland, OR

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, *Cum Laude*MINOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING.

Aug. 2019 - May 2023

Honors & Awards

2023 **NSF Graduate Research Fellowship**, GRFP

NSF

2023 **CS Outstanding Student Award**, For combination of coursework, research, and service.

U of Portland

2020 **Tau Beta Pi Induction**, National engineering honor society.

U of Portland

2019-2023 President's Scholarship

U of Portland

2019-2023 FIRST Robotics Scholarship

U of Portland

Professional Experience

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

June 2023 - Present

• Researching in computer architecture and computer systems.

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2022 - May 2023

- · Researched design methodologies for novel cache coherence protocols and designed protocols for cache-attached accelerators.
- Worked with Prof. Nathan Beckmann as part of the REU in Software Engineering.

Team LiftPortland, OR; Karonga, Malawi

SENIOR CAPSTONE

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

• Deployed a connected network of sensors and computation nodes in an infrastructure-limited environment in Malawi, Africa.

University of Portland

Portland, OR

Undergraduate Researcher

Jan. 2022 - May 2022

• Investigated CPU specialization methods to increase the performance and efficiency of Viterbi Decoding.

Intelligent, Complex, Adaptive, and Networks Lab

University of Portland

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2021 - August 2021

• Researched EEG-based view of comprehension of truth statements to understand how humans process undefined statements.

Publications _____

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

IEEE CAL 2023

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

WDDSA @ MICRO 2022

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Talks and Presentations

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators
Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators
Comparison of Computer Architecture Specialization Methods for Performance and

WDDSA @ MICRO, 2 Oct. 2022 SRC @ MICRO, 3 Oct. 2022 University of Portland Founders' Day, 12 April 2022

Service & Leadership

Tau Beta Pi
University of Portland

OREGON GAMMA CHAPTER PRESIDENT

2021 - 2022

· Responsible for planning meetings and activities to engage club members ranging from career development to design competitions.

Society of Women Engineers

University of Portland

MENTOR

2020 - 2023

• Mentored freshman girls in the engineering program.

Tutoring Working Group

University of Portland

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

Power Efficiency

2021

• Worked with faculty members to redesign the tutoring program for the Shiley School of Engineering following the Covid-19 pandemic to increase freshman and sophomore retention rates.

Teaching

University of Portland

Theory of Computation (CS 357)
Digital Systems Design (EE 332)
Signals & Systems (EE 262)
Logic Design (EE 231)
Electrical Circuits (EE 261)
Electrical Circuits Lab (EE 271)

Grader, Fall 2022
Tutor, Spring 2022
Tutor, Spring 2022
Grader and Tutor, Fall 2021
Tutor, Fall 2021-Spring 2022
Lab Assistant, Spring 2021

Skills

Programming Languages
Parallel Computing
Computer Architecture Tools
Other

Programming Languages C, C++, Python, Java, Assembly, MATLAB, Haskell, Verilog HDL, LaTeX

Experience in parallel algorithm design and programming using CUDA C++, OneTBB, and pthreads Experience using gem5, SLICC, McPat, Murphi Model Checker, CACTI, ProtoGen/HieraGen

Proficiency with Unix, SSH, Git/Github, Xcode, VSCode. Experience in Agile